别急着起来  再睡会儿
Don't get up yet. Stay in bed.
卡塞尔
Castle.
凯特  早啊
Kate. Hi.
-卡塞尔  -干什么
- Castle. - What?
这是你干的吗
Did you do this?
干什么
What?
别老问"什么"  清醒过来
Stop saying "what" and wake up.
我没有
I don't...
我们被铐住了
We're handcuffed.
重口啊
Kinky.
卡塞尔  这一点都不有趣
Castle, it's not funny.
我没说有趣  我说重口
I didn't say "Funny." I said "Kinky."
这不是我干的
And I didn't cuff us.
难道你觉得是我铐的吗
Well, y-you think I cuffed us?
这看起来像是警用手铐
Well, they look like police cuffs.
是别的什么人干的
Somebody else did this to us.
你认得出这是哪里吗
Do you recognize this place?
不知道
No.
不过  如果我在创作小说的话
But if I were writing a book,
这里就会是坏事上演的地方
this is where bad things would happen.
我的表不见了
My watch is missing.
我的也不在  钱包也没了
Mine, too, and my wallet.
还有我的警徽和枪
So is my badge and my gun.
还有我的手机  我才续过费的
And my phone. I just renewed my contract.
别嬉皮笑脸了
Would you stop joking?
我对你的应变方式可没做评论啊
Hey, do I begrudge you your coping mechanisms?
你记得的最后一件事是什么
What's the last thing that you remember?
我
I...
什么都想不起来
It's kind of a blur.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
我们大概被下了药
I think we were drugged.
我也这么想  而且还不是什么好药
Yeah, I think so, too, and not the good kind.
好
Okay.
把我的上衣掀起来
Lift my top.
你的药效大概还没退  不过我愿意效劳
I think you might still be under the influence, but okay.
卡塞尔  不是那样  看看我的背
Castle, not like that. Just check my back.
我有种刺痛感
There's something that hurts.
有个针眼
There's a needle mark.
我们的确是被下药了
We were drugged.
像是小矮人用吹箭筒射得一样
It looks like the work of a pygmy with a blowgun.
你可以把衣服放下了
Okay, you can put my shirt down.
-抱歉  -谢了
- Yeah, sorry. - Thanks.
卡塞尔  努力回想一下
All right, Castle, I want you to think very hard.
你记得今天早上发生的最后一件事是什么
What's the last thing that you remember from this morning?
我是和你在一起
I was with you.
我们在一个挺破的地方...
We were, uh, someplace seedy--
一个按钟点计费的旅店
a hotel that rents rooms by the hour.
你别开玩笑了行不
Would you just knock it off?
我们真的在那里
It's where we were.
你打电话叫我和你在那里碰面
You called me and you asked me to meet you there.
我的确是打了
Oh, I did. Yes.
然后我带你去了房间
And then I took you up to the room
然后我们
And then we...
我们就
尸体  我们去查看尸体了
Dead body. We went to go and see a dead body.
没错
Right.
一具尸体
A dead body.
知道我为什么喜欢和你共事吗
You know what I love about working with you?
你总能带我去最为迷人的地方
You always take me to the most charming places.
卡塞尔  我是个普通女孩
Well, I'm a simple girl, Castle.
尸体在哪儿我就去哪儿
I go where the bodies are.
而且对侦探小说家来说
Besides, for a mystery novelist,
破旅店不是常见的场景吗
aren't seedy motels kind of a standard?
没错  实际上
Ah, yes. Matter of fact,
它们的出现就代表会有色情事件发生
they're a veritable Advent Calendar of salaciousness.
每扇门之后  都有拨动人心的故事
Behind every door, a delightful tale
讲述了绝望  堕落
of desperation, depravity--
或是死亡
Or death.
你别那么像控制狂行不
You know, you need to stop being a control freak.
我才没有  你什么意思
I'm not--what do you mean, a control freak?
-你就是控制狂  -我才没有
- You are being a control freak. - I've never been a control freak.
抱歉  打扰到你们了吗
Sorry. Are we interrupting?
没事  死者是白人男性  奔四十
No. Victim's a white male, late 30s.
清洁工打扫房间时发现了他
Housekeeping found him when they came to clean the room.
死亡原因
Cause of death?
暂时还不清楚
Not entirely sure yet.
不过他面部有青紫的痕迹
But there are indications of asphyxia
所以可能是窒息而亡
with some cyanosis around the face.
就是说他是被人闷死的吗
So he was suffocated?
有可能  不过还有这个
Maybe. Then again, there's this.
针孔痕迹
Needle mark.
所以他可能吸毒过量后  脸朝下晕过去
So he could've just O.D.'ed, passed out face first,
-然后窒息了  -不  这绝对是谋杀
- and suffocated. - Oh, no. It's definitely murder.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
有人烧过他的手指
Someone torched his fingers.
把他的指纹都烧毁了
Burned off his prints.
他们想要掩盖他的身份
They wanted to erase his identity.
他们做得很不错
And they did a pretty good job, too.
他的钱包也不见了
His wallet's missing,
我们在房间里查找了几遍
and we've been through the room a couple of times.
没有线索能显示他的身份
There's nothing here to tell us who this guy is.
他的房钱是用现金付的吗
Did he pay for the room in cash?
是的  接待员说他是以
Yeah, and the clerk said
杰克·斯帕罗的身份登记的
that he registered as Jack Sparrow.
这有可能是他的真名
Oh, there's a possibility that's his real name.
是有这可能
Sure it is.
为以防万一  我们也在查这个名字
We're running it just in case.
接待员还说他办入住手续时很紧张
The clerk also said he appeared nervous when he checked in.
他一直往身后看
He, uh, kept looking behind him.
-有人来拜访他吗  -接待员不知道
- Did he have any visitors? - He couldn't say,
这里的保安系统也不太好
but this isn't the most secure building.
我看到大厅里有摄像头
I saw a camera in the lobby.
-那是个假的  -蠢货可不止那一个
- It's a dummy. - It's not the only one.
那是用来吓吓毒贩的
It's used to scare away drug dealers.
好了
Okay, um...
一般人不会大费周章隐瞒某人的身份
You don't go to the trouble of trying to erase someone's identity
除非是为了什么特殊的理由
unless you have a very good reason to.
蕾妮  你有可能恢复部分指纹吗
Lanie, what are the chances of us recovering some of the prints?
得看烧毁的情况如何
Depends on how bad the burns are.
我先把他带回停尸间吧
L-let me get him back to the morgue.
好  同时让莱恩
Okay, in the meantime, let's get Ryan
在失踪人口的照片里找找他
to run his photos through missing persons
看能不能查到什么
and... see if anything pops.
明白了
You got it.
破旧旅馆里被烧毁的指纹的无名氏
John Doe in a seedy motel with his fingerprints burned off.
我们怎么会从那里跑到了这里
How did we get from there to here?
慢点  慢点
Whoa, easy, easy there.
我不想废话
Hate to state the obvious,
但我们现在是同一根稻草上的蚂蚱
but we're kind of joined at the hip here.
我们先起来吧  快点
Okay, let's just get up. Come on.
你早上总是这个样子吗
Are you always like this in the morning?
真是
Oh, this is...
-真是难办了  -没错
- This is awkward. - Yeah.
就不能正常地把我们铐在一起吗
They couldn't just handcuff us "Midnight Run" style?
等等  莱恩在失踪人口里查找了死者
Wait a minute. Ryan did run our guy through missing persons,
没人对得上  然后呢
and there wasn't a match. Then what?
然后
Then...
莱恩问我
Ryan asked me...
如果他在自己家过了感恩节
if he spent Thanksgiving at his family's house,
是不是意味着他就得去
did that mean he had to spend Christmas
珍妮家过圣诞了
at Jenny's family's house?
卡塞尔  我在说我们的案子
Castle, I'm talking about our case.
你要我重现记忆  我就得照着顺序来
If you want me to reconstruct it, I have to do it in order.
好吧  随你
Okay, fine. Um...
指纹被烧毁  窒息身亡
Burnt fingerprints, suffocated,
针孔痕迹
uh... needle marks.
停尸间  我们去了停尸间
The morgue. We went to the morgue.
我说了  这不关你的事
I told you, it's none of your business.
当然不关我的事
Of course it's none of my business,
所以我才想知道嘛
that's why I want to know.
知道啥
Know what?
她和埃斯波西托在吵什么
What she and Esposito were fighting about.
这根本不关你的事
It's none of your business.
越不关己越要问
That's the point.
有什么发现吗
Where are we?
暂时还没有查明身份
No I.D. Yet,
但他的手上有茧
but his hands have calluses,
所以他极有可能是从事体力劳动
so most likely, he had a job that required physical labor.
指纹呢
What about fingerprints?
皮肤表层烧毁得太严重了
Outer skin's too damaged.
不过  我把皮肤泡软后
But... I may be able to macerate the skin,
也许能从硬膜层下面取到指纹
pull some from the underside of the epidural layer.
你能办到吗
You can do that?
有时候可以
Yes, in some cases.
不过这得花上几天时间
But it's gonna take a couple of days.
与此同时  我发现了这个
In the meantime, I did find this.
这个被折起来塞进他的裤袋里
It was tucked in the fold of his pants pocket.
杀手很容易忽略它
It would've been real easy for our killer to miss.
97号大街西147号  下午4点
"147 West 97th Street, 4:00 p.m."
那是坎博瑞咖啡店的地址
It's the address of the Cambury Cafe,
就在百老汇半个街区外
half block off Broadway.
下午4点  他要去见某个人
4:00 p.m. He was meeting someone.
也可能是遇到了谁
Or met someone.
你和埃斯波西托带这张照片过去
Okay, you and Esposito take this up there and see
看看有没有人记得见过死者
if anyone remembers seeing our victim.
或许可以帮助我们确认他的身份
Maybe that'll help us I.D. him.
这就去
On it.
这个死者究竟有何特殊之处
What was so special about our victim
以至于凶手想要掩盖他的身份
that our killer wanted to erase his identity?
不要说间谍
Don't say spy.
也别说是黑帮干的
Or mob hit.
那黑帮干掉了一个间谍呢
Mob hit of a spy?
异想天开对目前状况毫无帮助
Crazy theories aren't gonna help,
我们还是得先确认他的身份
not until we figure out who this guy is.
贝克特
Beckett?
什么事
What?
这是邮政条形码
This is a postal bar code.
死者把便条写在一张信封的背面
Our victim wrote this note on the back of an envelope.
邮政条形码
A postal bar code?
是的  就是那些邮件标签
Yeah, those little hash marks
或者信封上的散列标示
you see on mailing labels and envelopes,
是一种精确指示地址的方法
it's a way of exactly identifying an address.
但是只能通过机读
But in a machine-readable way.
只要我们解读出这个条形码
We get that decoded,
就能知道死者写下这张纸条时
we'll be able to tell exactly where our victim was
他究竟在哪
when he wrote that note.
是的  那之后我们打电话给邮局
Okay, then we called the post office,
他们给了我们一个地址
and they gave us the address.
-皇后区的房子  -皇后区的房子
- The house in Queens. - The house in Queens.
你知道蕾妮和埃斯波西托为什么拌嘴吗
So do you know what Lanie and Esposito were fighting about?
几乎各种事
Everything.
他们都想复合
They both want to be together,
但是两人都不愿承认这一点
but neither of them wants to admit to it.
相爱的人为何要如此折磨彼此
Ugh. Why do people do that to themselves?
大概他们都没意识到吧
Maybe they just don't see it.
怎么会没意识到  这多明显啊
How could they not? It's so obvious.
就是这里吗
This is the place?
根据地址是这儿了
Matches the address.
看起来没人在家啊
Doesn't look like anybody's home.
有人在吗
Hello?
纽约警局  有人在吗
NYPD. Anybody here?
你好
Hello?
有人在吗
Anybody here?
比尔和诺拉·瑞福德
Bill and Nora Ranford.
或许这个比尔就是我们的死者
Maybe Bill is our john doe.
纽约警局  请自报姓名
NYPD. Identify yourself.
帮帮我
Help me.
女士
Ma'am.
女士  你还好吗
Ma'am, are you okay?
一个老妇人  关在笼子里
And an old woman in a cage.
这是我记得的最后一件事
Yeah, that's the last thing I remember.
我也是
Me, too.
到底发生了什么事
What the hell is going on?
只是过去我总是与我的家人共度圣诞
It's just, I always spend Christmas with my family.
话虽如此
Right. Well,
但是谁要你自己选择了结婚
you were the one who decided to get hitched, bro.
但这不表示我愿意大老远开车到佛罗里达
Yeah, but I didn't think that meant driving down to Florida
跟她的祖母一起过节
to spend the holidays with her grandmother.
开车去  你不坐飞机吗
Driving? You're not flying?
节日里坐飞机  你开什么玩笑
During the holidays? Are you kidding me?
另外  珍妮觉得公路旅行
Besides, Jenny thinks that, a-a road trip
可以让我们享受美好的二人时光
will give us some quality time together.
那可不是简单的公路旅行  兄弟
That is no road trip, brother.
那是...
That...
一种情感考验
is a relationship test.
情感考验
A relationship test?
我们一个月后就要结婚了
We're getting married in a month.
那得等考验结束再说了
Well, we'll see what happens after the test.
这是婚前公路旅行考验
It's the pre-wedding road trip test.
两人在几个小时里单独呆在一起
Locked together for hours,
如果她心里有任何关于未来生活的不确定
that way she can confront you with any lingering doubts
都可以在这时向你提出来
she may have about your future together.
而你...无处可躲  非答不可
And you... will have nowhere to hide.
你们谁见到贝克特了吗
Have either of you seen Beckett?
她应该正在追查线索
She's probably following up on a lead.
不要以为我不知道
Don't think that I don't know
你们几个总是互相打掩护
that you guys cover for each other.
什么意思
What's that?
关于死者有何进展了
Any progress on our John Doe?
调查证实他昨天确实去过坎博瑞咖啡厅
Yeah. Turned out, he did show up at the Cambury Cafe yesterday,
而且他不是一个人
and he wasn't alone.
服务员立刻认出了他
Waitress recognized him immediately,
说他坐在角落位置
said he sat in the corner booth,
与一个长头发  山羊胡子的男子在一起
met with a guy-- long hair, goatee--
而且死者显得很紧张
said our vic looked nervous.
我们正让这个服务员与画师合作
We have the waitress working with an artist
看能不能画出这个山羊胡子男的肖像
to see if we can come up with a sketch of the goateed man
以用来做排查
to use on a canvass.
很好  随时向我汇报进展
All right. Keep me apprised.
珍妮这么爱我  她不会这样考验我的
Come on, Jenny loves me. She wouldn't test me like that.
是啊
Right.
如果她要带你去湖上泛舟你也要小心
Just watch out if she wants to take you canoeing.
懂了吗
Okay?
泛舟  那也是考验吗
Canoeing? C-canoeing is a test?
泛舟关键在于力度与方向
It's all about power, direction,
婚姻关系也是如此
like a marriage.
如果船能一路向前
If the canoe goes straight,
则向她证明了你能为她做出让步
it shows her that you can compromise,
并肩合作  找到节奏
work together, find a rhythm,
两人可以朝一个方向共同前进
move forward in the same direction.
但是  如果你们一直在原地打转
But if it's going around in circles,
那恐怕你们的关系也会如此
so is your relationship.
卡塞尔  你就不能配合着我一点
Castle, would you just work with me?
为什么不是你配合我
How about you work with me?
为什么总是你来作主
How come you always have to lead?
你为什么老是给我惹祸
How come you always have to step on my toes?
我什么时候  好吧  你知道吗
Since when do I-- okay, you know what?
告诉我
Tell me this--
你为什么总是要走在最前面
Why do you always have to be first?
第一个走出电梯
First out of the elevator,
第一个进出门
first through the door.
我是警察  我佩枪而你没有
Um, I am a cop. I'm the one with a gun.
所以先进门是我的职责所在
Being first through the door is my job.
在电梯里也是
In the elevator?
这么说吧
Look, how about this?
偶尔让别人帮你开次门
Would it kill ya to let someone open the door for you
你会死啊
once in a while?
但是你应该想到  如果让别人帮我开门
You do realize, if somebody opens the door for me,
我还是要走在前面的  是吧
then I will be going through it first anyway, right?
对了  我都忘了
Oh, yeah, that's right. I forgot.
你还总得做那个最聪明的
You have to be the smartest, too.
所有事情对你来说都像一场竞赛
Everything's a competition with you.
这根本不是事实
That is so not true.
你早上总是这个样子吗
Are you always like this in the mornings?
你知道吗  我倒想跟你争辩
You know, I'd argue with you,
但最终也只能让着你
but then I'd have to let you win.
好吧  那听你的  你来带路
Okay, fine. Go ahead. You lead.
多谢
Thank you.
你想往哪边走
Where did you want to go?
我好像看到那边有灯的开关
I think that there's a light switch over there.
还是你宁可呆在黑暗中
Or do you want to stay in the dark?
看来还是不开灯的时候好一点
I liked it better in the dark.
这门是钢做的  我们不可能从这儿出去
This door is steel. There's no way we're getting through here.
这些墙壁是煤渣砖造的
These walls are cinder block.
你猜这个大冰柜里有什么
What do you suppose is in that big freezer?
会不会是那个老妇人
You think it's the old woman?
我们会不会是被关在了变态狂的老巢里
I mean, what if we're in some psycho's lair
得杀死对方才能活下去  就像《电锯惊魂》那样
and we have to kill each other, like in "Saw"?
卡塞尔  别胡思乱想了  对我们毫无用处
Castle, stop speculating. It's not helping.
拜托  一个老妇人被关在笼子里
Oh, come on. An old lady in a cage,
我们又被铐在一起关在这个诡异的房间里
us cuffed together in this creepy room.
我还能怎么想
What am I supposed to think?
你该想  我们得
You're supposed to think that we need
赶在有人回来之前离开这里
to get the hell outta here before someone comes back.
你觉得我们呆在这儿有多久了
How long do you think we were out?
几个小时了吧
Couple of hours.
你怎么知道的
How can you tell?
因为我饿了呗
'Cause I'm hungry.
我这儿有些牛肉干
I got some beef jerky.
怎么了
What?
牵住我的手
Hold my hand.
这样手铐才不会一直割到我们
So the cuffs don't cut into us.
为什么不试着打开它
We could just try to get 'em off.
你有发夹吗
You got a bobby pin?
你以为这是四十年代啊
What is this, the 1940s?
这是我的警用手铐
These are my police cuffs.
怎么可能让你用个发夹就能打开
You're not gonna open them with a bobby pin.
面对现实吧
Face it.
我们被困住了
We're stuck.
你觉得会有人注意到我们不见了吗
Think anyone knows we're missing?
你没回家  玛莎和阿丽克西斯会注意吧
Martha and Alexis will notice if you don't go home, right?
事实上  我妈这周末带阿丽克西斯
Actually, my mother's taking Alexis
去大学校园游了
on a tour of colleges this weekend.
埃斯波西托和莱恩
Esposito and Ryan--
他们可能会注意到  但这也不表示他们
Yeah, they'll probably notice, but it doesn't mean they'll...
能找到我们
find us here.
那是什么
What is that?
是个活板门
It's a hatch.
如果我们能爬上去  说不定就能逃出去
If we can get up there, we might be able to get out.
说得简单  这太高了
Yeah, well, it's too high.
如果我们爬到那上面就可以了
Not if we climb on top of that.
蕾妮打来的
That was Lanie.
初步尸检报告显示死者
Preliminary autopsy report shows that our victim
确实是窒息致死
was in fact smothered.
像他这样的大个子  相信肯定挣扎了一番
Guy his size, you'd think he'd put up more of a struggle.
他没法挣扎  毒检报告显示
He couldn't. Tox report showed that
他体内含有的镇定剂
his system was flooded with so much sedative
都足够放倒一头大象了
that it could put down an elephant.
嫌犯肖像进展如何
Where are we with that sketch?
我让警员在嫌犯照片里面找
Well, I got unis looking through mug books
我还派了一队人去城外排查
and I sent a team uptown to canvass.
还没回来吗
Still not back, huh?
没有
No.
已经好几个小时了
It's been hours.
每次我打过去  都直接转到语音信箱
Every time I call, it goes straight to voice mail.
你认为他们真是去追查线索了吗
You think they're really running down a lead?
什么线索
What lead?
我们回来的时候板上没有新的东西
There was nothing new on the board when we came back.
你能不能问一下调度
You think you can hit up dispatch,
看看他们能不能追踪到
see if they'll run a trace on
贝克特车上的应答机
the transponder in Beckett's unit?
我想知道他们在哪
I want to know where they are.
天呐  这个角度我用不上力
Ohh! I can't get a good angle on it.
好吧  这样呢
Yeah. Try this.
准备好了吗
Ready?
你最好别乐在其中  卡塞尔
You better not be enjoying this, Castle.
我等会儿再向你汇报
I'll let you know in a minute.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
用力
Push.
好了
Oh. Okay.
不管这里面是什么鬼东西都比
Whatever's in here is a hell of a lot heavier
一个小老太太重多了
than a little old lady.
就好像  就好像里面装满了石头
It's like... it's filled with rocks.
如果我们把它清空呢
What if we emptied it?
真是个好主意  卡塞尔
That's a great idea, Castle,
只是这箱子被锁起来了  而且我也没带撬锁钳
except it's locked, and I'm fresh out of bolt cutters.
是的  但这是个密码锁
Yeah, but it's a combo lock.
那又怎样
So?
我在写《风暴骤起》的时候
So when I was writing "Storm rising",
我师从道上最好的开锁匠之一
I studied with one of the best safe crackers in the biz.
我能打开这个  只是我不知道我们要不要打开
I can open this. I just don't know if we want to.
开锁吧  卡塞尔
Let's get crackin', Castle,
趁绑架我们的人还没回来
before our captors get back.
应答机显示她的车就在这里
Transponder says her unit's right over here.
那绝对是贝克特的车
That's definitely Beckett's car.
看上去是被丢弃在这里
Looks like it's been dumped.
是的  报告上去
Yeah, call it in.
时间标识显示这是五个小时之前
Time stamp puts this at five hours ago.
那是贝克特的车
So that's Beckett's car.
但那既不是卡塞尔也不是贝克特
But that's not Castle or Beckett.
而且他不是一个人  有人来接他了
And he's not alone. Someone picked him up.
知道他们是谁吗
Do we know who they are?
不知道
No clue.
能看到车牌号吗
Can we get a plate number?
太远了
Too far away.
我还追踪了贝克特和卡塞尔的手机
I also ran Beckett and Castle's cells.
两个人都找不到
They're both off grid.
卡塞尔到底给她惹了什么麻烦
What the hell did Castle get her into?
我要鉴证组彻底搜查
I want C.S.U. on that car
那辆车里所有能找到的证据
with a fine-tooth comb for any possible trace evidence.
他们在和你们一起调查无名氏
They were working the John Doe with you.
他们到底去哪了
Where could they have gone?
我们讨论好几次了  还是不知道
Been over it a dozen times. We still don't know.
而且还没有找到咖啡店里的那个长发男人
And still no hits on our long-haired man from the cafe.
不管怎样都要查到死者的身份
Do whatever it takes to get an I.D. on that victim
搞清楚他到底在干什么
and find out what in the hell he was into.
如果贝克特和卡塞尔还在外面的话
If Beckett and Castle are still out there,
那么他们的时间不多了
then they're running out of time.
天呐  卡塞尔
Oh, for god sake, Castle.
你到底还要鼓弄多长时间
How much longer are you gonna keep doing this?
我马上就要成功了
Oh, I almost had it.
是的  你快成功都一百次了
Yeah. Like you had it the last hundred times.
有点信心好吗
Oh, ye of little faith.
谁要是跟你连体一定很痛苦
You know, you would make a terrible conjoined twin.
可以把手还给我了吗
Can I have my hand back?
你有没有可以解释这一切的理论
So you got a story to explain all of this--
笼子里的老妇人
The old woman in the cage,
身份被有意掩盖的无名氏
John Doe with his identity removed,
我们被锁在一起但还活着
us handcuffed but still alive?
是的  我可不认为你会喜欢我的理论
Yeah, I don't think that's a story you want to hear.
为什么
Why not?
这些元素加在一起
With those elements,
我可想不出一个有好结局的版本
I can't think of a version that ends well,
迪士尼童话版本也没有
Not even a Disney version.
我就怕这样
Yeah, I was afraid of that.
好消息是  我们已经失踪了一段时间
The good news is, we've been gone long enough,
他们现在应该已经开始找我们了
They've started to look for us by now.
一百零一次说不定会成功
Hundred and first time's the charm?
拜托了  蕾妮  这家伙的尸检
Come on, Lanie. There's gotta be
肯定还找到些别的线索
something else about this guy from this autopsy.
他处于心脏病的前期
He was in the beginning stages of heart disease.
他有髋部退化的症状
He had a degenerative hip condition,
还有轻微的脊椎侧凸
and mild scoliosis,
大概是因为坐的时间太长了
probably from sitting too much,
还有他吃的最后一顿
and the last thing he had to eat
是一个五香烟熏牛肉三明治
was a pastrami sandwich--
没有一个能用来确定他的身份
none of which will get you an I.D.
他的双手上有老茧  说明他从事体力劳动
His hands were callused, suggesting physical labor,
可他还长时间坐着
and yet--and yet, he spent too much time sitting?
可能他是开铲车的  我不知道
Maybe he drove a forklift. I don't know.
拜托  我们现在就需要些有力的线索
Come on. We need something concrete, now.
那我没法帮你
Then I can't help you.
蕾妮  他们下落不明
Lanie, they're out there.
天知道他们在哪里或是惹上了什么麻烦
God knows where or what kind of trouble they're in.
你以为我不想帮忙吗  他们也是我的朋友
You don't think I want to help? They're my friends, too.
贝克特说过
So Beckett said,
时间足够的话  你说不定能复原指纹
with enough time, you might be able to recover prints.
是的  要几天时间  怎么了
Yeah, in a couple of days. Why?
如果你现在就做会怎么样
What happens if you do it now?
指纹可能会被破坏而且再也无法鉴定了
I could damage the print beyond recognition.
可能  这么说还是有成功的机会  是吧
"Could." So it's possible that it might not, right?
我们必须得做点什么
We gotta do something.
成功了
I did it.
-你成功了  -太好了
- You did it!  - Ha ha!
还能有多糟呢
How bad can it be?
我是说  我们见到过尸体的  对吧
I mean, we've seen dead bodies before, right?
是的
Right.
这不是尸体
It's not a body.
不是
No.
比那还糟
It's worse.
是镣铐和血淋淋的刑具
Manacles and bloody instruments of torture.
看来你那疯狂残暴心理变态杀手的理论
Yeah, looks like your crazed, sadistic, psycho killer theory
说不定是真的  卡塞尔
might not be far off, Castle.
我不知道是该高兴还是害怕
Well, I don't know whether to be smug or horrified.
要我说是受到激励
I vote for motivated.
说的是  我们得赶快逃出这个鬼地方
Right you are. Let's get the hell outta here.
哈维尔
Javi.
干嘛
What?
我能感到你的不耐烦都吹在我背上了
I can feel your impatience all over my backside,
永远不要催我
and rushing me is never a good idea.
你说的是指纹  是吧
You're talking about that print, right?
见鬼
Damn it.
-怎么了  -指纹撕破了
- What?  - It tore.
我猜是皮肤还不够柔软
I guess the skin wasn't softened enough.
指纹毁了
It's ruined.
还有能用的地方吗
Is any of it usable?
我说不定能恢复中间残留的部分  怎么了
I might be able to salvage some from the middle. Why?
所以我们做的是
So what we did...
我们设法将纸片上残留的部分指纹
Was, we were able to join the partials from that scrap of paper
和蕾妮恢复的部分结合在一起
with the, uh, print pieces that Lanie recovered.
死者名叫汉克·斯布纳
Our victim is Hank Spooner.
是圣安东尼奥的一个独立卡车司机
An independent trucker out of San Antonio.
开的是自己的卡车
Owns and operates his own rig.
他到纽约来干什么
What was he doing in New York?
根据他的家人所说  他上周接了一笔生意
Well, according to his folks, he got a contract last week
到德州的德里奥运送
to pick up a load from Del Rio, Texas,
一批货物到皇后区
and bring it to Queens.
他们最后一次联系是两天前
Last they heard from him was two days ago.
他运的是什么货
What was the cargo?
斯布纳只告诉他们他临时接到一个
Well, all Spooner told 'em was he got a last-minute call
特殊客户的通知并付给他一大笔钱
from a special client who was paying him big money.
他的家人还说
His folks also said,
他一般不会住汽车旅馆
it's unusual for him to be staying in a motel.
斯布纳从不呆在城里
Apparently, Spooner never stayed in the city.
他认为呆在他的卡车里更安全也更便宜
He thought it was safer and cheaper to stay in his truck.
我们得找到那辆卡车
We need to find that vehicle.
在所有主要卡车道路关卡发布全面通缉
Get an A.P.B. out to all the major truck stops.
如果我们幸运的话  它或许能告诉我们
If we're lucky, it may tell us
为什么有人想要汉克·斯布纳的命
why someone wanted Hank Spooner dead.
我想我能帮你回答这个问题
I think maybe I can help answer that.
在找我吗
You looking for me?
查克·马丁内兹  缉毒局
Chuck Martinez, D.E.A.
你是怎么知道我们在找你的  马丁内兹探员
How did you know we were looking for you, agent Martinez?
我们标记了斯布纳的档案
We had Spooner's files tagged.
他是犯罪嫌疑人  你们调查他的指纹时
He's a person of interest, so I got notified
有人通知了我
when you ran his prints.
你昨天为什么跟他见面
Why did you meet with him yesterday?
你的嫌疑人已经死了  马丁内兹探员
Your man's dead, Agent Martinez,
我的两名手下失踪了
and two of my folks are missing.
我们没时间计较管辖权的问题了
We don't have time for jurisdictional games,
我再问你一次  你为什么盯上斯布纳
so I'll ask you again, what's your interest in Spooner?
好吧
All right.
每年大概五六次
About a half a dozen times a year,
斯布纳会从德克萨斯运东西到纽约
Spooner takes a contract from Texas to New York,
但他总会在德里奥装点货
but he always makes a pick up in Del Rio.
那是个边境小镇
It's a little border town.
你怀疑他从墨西哥走私毒品吗
You think he's smuggling drugs from Mexico?
贩毒集团在这些城镇非常活跃
The cartels are really active in these towns.
他们极其残暴
They're extremely brutal.
既然你认为斯布纳涉案
And if you knew Spooner was involved,
你为什么不逮捕他
why didn't you arrest him?
所有迹象都很明显
All the signs were there, okay?
但除了可疑活动我们没有其他证据
But all we had him on was suspicious activity,
我们想抓的不是小喽罗
and we don't want the errand boy.
我们想要的是指挥他的人
We want the people he works for.
你们怎么会在咖啡厅见面
How'd you end up at that cafe?
我们需要实打实的证据
We needed some leverage.
所以我们布了个局
So we set up a sting,
假装雇他为我们运货
Posing as runners looking to hire him to move some product,
不过斯布纳识破了我的人
Only Spooner made my guy.
斯布纳不但没有跑路  还想面谈
Now instead of running, Spooner ...he wanted to meet.
他很害怕
Okay? And he was scared.
他想退出  他很担心如果他退出
He wanted out, and he was afraid of what they would do to him
他们会如何对付他
if he walked away.
所以他同意如果我可以保证他的安全
So he agreed to tell us everything
他会把一切都告诉我们
if I guaranteed him safety,
我向我的上司报告了情况  他们同意了
and I took that to my bosses, they agreed.
但到那时  他已经死了
But by then, he was already dead.
是的
Right.
失陪
Excuse me.
你的同事在哪失踪的
So where were your colleagues when they went missing?
不知道
We don't know.
我们只知道他们在追查这案子
We just know they were on the case.
斯布纳有跟你说过这个"纽约行动"吗
Did Spooner say anything to you about the New York operation?
他只说了
All he said was,
这跟你们想的不一样
"It's not at all what you think."
州警在城北
Troopers found a semi.
发现了一辆货车
Truck stop north of the city.
行动吧  伙计们
Let's go, boys.
据卡车停站记录
According to truck stop records,
这辆大卡车已经停在这三天了
the rig's been parked here for three days.
这两天没人看到司机
No one's seen the driver for two.
你来看看里面吧
You're gonna want to take a look inside.
头发
That's hair.
这些可能是气孔
These could be air holes.
嘿  这里
Hey, over here.
还是太高
Still too high.
我站到你肩膀就够高了
Not if I climb on your shoulders.
怎么了  我们之前干过啊
What? We've done it before.
是啊  好像那次很轻松很愉快似的
Yeah, you say that like it was pleasant,
再说那时我们没被铐在一起
and we weren't handcuffed.
看看现在是谁没信心了
Who's got no faith now?
来吧  卡塞尔  不知道他们什么时候会回来
Come on, Castle. We have no idea when they're coming back
或者他们根本就不会回来
or even if they're coming back at all.
上次你穿的是运动鞋
Last time, you were wearing sneakers.
好吧
Fine.
我需要你帮我一下
I think I'm gonna need your help.
掀起我的衣服  脱掉我的靴子
"Lift up my shirt, pull off my boots."
一般情况下
You know, under normal circumstances,
我会很享受接下来该发生的事
I would like where this was heading.
你可以等我们逃出去之后再继续幻想
You can fantasize later, after we get out of the room.
哎  你一同意  乐趣全无
Just so you know, not as much fun if I have your permission.
穿这个你怎么跑啊
How do you run in these things?
闭上嘴  脱就好
Shut up and pull.
马丁内兹探员  你确定他们是在走私毒品吗
Agent Martinez, are you sure these guys were smuggling drugs?
如果我确定的话我会很乐意分享
You know, if I had answers, I'd share.
-盖茨警监  -有什么发现
- Captain Gates. - What'd you find?
-运货单  -两天前斯布纳
- Waybills. - Spooner delivered
给南曼哈顿区的家具店送过一次货
to a furniture store in lower Manhattan two days ago.
去查查
Get on it.
给你的上司们打电话
Call your bosses.
告诉他们我要此案的所有文件
Tell 'em I want all the files on this investigation.
我要找回我的人
I'm getting my people back.
准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
-好了  -一
- Ready. - One.
二
Two.
三  噢  天啊
Three. Oh! Oh, jeez.
卡塞尔
Castle!
把我放下  好吗
Okay, can you put me down?
小心点
Okay. Easy.
如果能从这里出去
If we ever get outta here,
我们真应该考虑加入马戏团
we should seriously consider joining the circus.
让我从后面试下好吗
Let me try it from behind, okay?
好吧
All right. I'm game.
好的
Okay.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Ready.
一  二
One. Two.
三
Three.
好的  好的
Oh, okay. Oh. Okay.
我要举右手了  准备好没
Okay, I'm lifting my right hand. Ready?
好了
Okay.
没我想象的那么有意思
Not so fun as I would've thought.
真是受不了你总是骑在我头上唉
You know, I'm getting a little tired of you walking all over me.
是开的
It's open.
我觉得我可以把我的...
Okay, I think I can pull my...
嘿  放我们出去
Hey! Let us outta here!
你要怎样
What do you want from us?
盖茨警监
Captain Gates.
家具店老板证实了两天前
The furniture store owner verified that he took delivery
他收到了斯布纳的运货
from Spooner a couple of days ago.
但是他说只是几张咖啡桌而已
But he said it was just a couple of coffee tables,
装在卡车尾部
packed near the rear of the truck.
你相信他所说的
And you believed him?
他是个有家室的人  没有前科
He's a family man, didn't have any priors.
不过他提到说卸货的时候
But he did say something happened during the delivery,
有点奇怪
something weird.
他们卸货的时候
As they were unloading the shipment,
有个盒子掉下来砸到他肩上
a box fell off a stack and hit him in the shoulder.
他说那个箱子是空的
He said the box must have been empty,
因为箱子从他肩上弹开了
'cause it bounced right off of him.
他本想跟斯布纳开个玩笑
He tried to joke with Spooner,
问他是在运棉花糖还是空气
asked him if he was shipping cotton candy or air,
但斯布纳变得很不自在
but Spooner kind of got squirrely, said it was just
说那只是填空间的几个空箱子
a couple of empties that were packed there to fill some space.
店主没觉得是什么大事
The owner thought it wasn't a big deal,
可之后他听到箱子后面有些什么声音
but then he heard something from behind the boxes,
听起来像是呼吸声
something that sounded like breathing.
也就是说斯布纳做一些小的合法工作
So Spooner takes a few small, legitimate jobs
只是为走私做掩护
in order to justify his smuggling trips,
在他真正运送的货物前摆上空盒子
and places a wall of empties in front of whatever his real cargo is.
店主知道斯布纳要去什么地方吗
Did the owner have any idea where Spooner was headed?
不知道
None.
贝克特和卡塞尔查到了线索
Beckett and Castle were on to something.
他们到底去哪儿了
Where in the hell did they go?
当时我们查到的线索就只有这个地址
Well, the only thing we had at the time was this address.
但我们已经派人调查了
And we were already covering it.
他们一定看到或听到了什么你们没发现的
Oh, they must have seen or heard something that you didn't.
好吧  我要你们去...
Okay, I want you guys to...
上  上  上
Go! Go! Go!
纽约警局
NYPD!
原地待命
Hold position!
房间安全
Room clear!
安全
Clear!
这地方是空的
This place is empty.
你真觉得这就是他们来的地方吗
You really think this is where they went?
如果是的话  现在也不在了
If they were here, they're not here now.
嘿  警探  这里
Hey, Detective. Look in here.
好像是个活板门
There's some kind of hatch.
好了  封起来  以待调查
All right. Let's seal it off and process it.
该死
Damn it.
这是钢的  卡塞尔
It's hard-cased steel, Castle.
不用钥匙打不开
We're not getting out of these without keys.
还有一个方法
You know, there is another way.
我们不去破坏手铐
We don't go through the cuffs.
你是说...
You... mean...
《疯狂的麦克斯》  《127小时》
"Mad Max." "127 Hours."
你是要砍断你的手吗
Are you offering to cut off your own hand?
哇哦  我的  不  我在考虑砍你的手
Whoa. Mine? No. I was thinking about yours.
我的手  为什么是我的手
My hand? Why my hand?
因为比我的小
It's smaller.
他们来了
They're coming.
告诉他这价钱已经很不错了
Tell him it's a good price.
如果他中意她  我手上还有两个
And if he likes her, I got two more that fell into my lap
我可以给你打个折
that I could sell you at a discount.
我现在得把她们转移
I just need to move 'em now.
听起来像阿拉伯语
That sounds like Arabic.
他们去旁边房间了
They're going to the other room.
卡塞尔  房间里有人
Castle, someone else is in there.
她很漂亮
She is very beautiful.
完全符合你的要求
Just like you asked.
他们还关着别人
They're holding someone else.
那个老女人吗
The old woman?
不  像是个女孩  好像
No, it's more like a girl, like--
像是他们打算卖掉她
Like they're trying to sell her.
人口贩卖
It's human trafficking.
原来是这样
That's what this is.
他们在拐卖人口
They're abducting and selling people.
这就是我们现在还活着的原因
That's why we're still alive.
他们不会杀我们  他们要把我们卖掉
They're not gonna kill us. They're gonna sell us.
怎么了嘛  我的小说很畅销的
What? I'm a best-selling author.
我在想我值多少钱
I wonder what I'd be worth.
还是别研究了  好吗
Let's not find out, okay?
好吧  可还是...
Yeah, still...
有什么发现吗
Anything?
从切割痕迹来看
From the cut marks,
活板门应该是刚弄的
looks like this hatch was just installed.
知道原因吗
Any idea why?
不知道
No.
鉴证组会来采集指纹和其他线索
C.S.U. is gonna sweep for prints and trace.
邻居们怎么说
What did the neighbors say?
银行在六个月前取消了前任房主
Ah, that the bank foreclosed on the previous owners,
比尔和诺拉·瑞福德的抵押赎回权
Bill and Nora Ranford, six months ago,
但是几周前  有新住户搬进来了
but a couple of weeks ago, new neighbors moved in.
查到是谁吗
Get an I.D.?
他们很低调
They kinda kept a low profile.
但邻居们说是两个人
But neighbors think that there were two of them,
两兄弟  邻居看清了他们开的车
brothers, and they got an I.D. on their ride.
黑色的F-150
Black F-150.
A black F-150?
那就意味着贝克特和卡塞尔来过这
That means Beckett and Castle were here.
还不止  几天前的晚上
Not only that, but a couple of nights ago,
街对面的人说他
guy from across the street
大半夜听到很大响声
says he hears some noises in the middle of the night.
所以他走到窗前  看到一辆大卡车正在停靠
So he goes to the window, and sees a semi pulling up.
斯布纳也在这吗
Spooner was here, too?
对  不管这是怎么一回事
Yeah. Whatever was going on,
一切都发生在这里
this was the place.
你去叫醒登记员
Why don't you wake up the registrar?
看看是谁买了这栋房子
See who bought this property.
我要知道这帮家伙到底是谁
I want to know who these guys are.
有人吗  你听得见我们说话吗
Hello, can you hear us?
卡塞尔  我能听到呼吸声
Castle, I can hear somebody breathing.
也许她被打了镇静剂
Maybe she's sedated.
有人吗  你听得见我们说话吗
Hello. Can you hear us?
墙是瓷砖粉刷的
This wall is stucco and tile.
所以呢
So?
其他地方都是空心煤渣砖
So the others are all cinder block.
如果我们开始慢慢敲
If we start digging,
也许能把墙打穿  过去帮她
we might be able to break through and help her.
从一个密室换到另一个密室
How is getting out of one prison and into another
对我们有帮助吗
gonna help any of us?
那我问你
Well, let me ask you this,
如果现在被关在那边的是阿丽克西斯
if it was Alexis on the other side,
你会怎么做
what would you do?
好的  知道了
Yeah. Okay.
有新的消息就打给我  谢了
The moment you hear. Thanks.
鉴定组的电话
C.S.U.?
是的  在房子里找不到任何指纹
Yeah. Negative on prints from the house.
房子被清洗过
Place was wiped.
你在登记员那查到什么没
What'd you get from the registrar?
房子五个月前被取消抵押回赎权
Well, the house was foreclosed on five months ago,
现在还是归国家银行所有
it's still owned by National Bank.
疑犯肯定是非法占用的
Our guys must have been squatting.
你刚是说国家银行吗
Did you say National Bank?
是的  有什么问题吗
Yeah, why?
马丁内兹刚刚拿过来的文件
The files agent Martinez sent over.
等等
Hang on.
斯布纳两个月前往布鲁克林的房子送了次货
Spooner made a delivery to a Brooklyn house two months ago.
几天之后
A couple of days later,
联邦政府的官员对那房子进行了突击搜查
the feds raided the place.
但警察到那时  人去楼空了
But by then, whoever was in the house was gone.
他们发现地板上被凿了个洞
All they found was a hatch cut into the floor,
通往地下室
which accessed the basement.
听起来跟这件案子很像
Sounds familiar.
但当他们调查房产时
Yeah, but when they traced the property,
发现房子归银行所有  国家银行
it was bank owned, by National Bank.
疑犯肯定是专门找那些被取消抵押回赎权
Our guys must be targeting distressed properties
等着出售的房子来做事
to run their operations from.
找到所有纽约地区归国家银行
Okay, get a list of all the National Bank-owned
所有的房子
properties in the New York area,
从有地下室的开始逐一排查
starting with the properties that have a basement.
如果他们利用国家银行的取消回赎房产单
If they're working off the National Bank foreclosure list,
也就可以找到安全的房子了
that may be where they're finding their safe houses.
好了  这边应该可以了
Okay, that should do it.
换个位置
Shift.
好的
Okay.
好了  你准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
好了
Ready.
踹吧
Go.
再换个姿势
Shift over.
好
Okay.
好了
一起来  准备好了吗
Together. Ready?
好了  开始
Yeah. Go.
我一直对你的双腿情有独钟
I've always liked your legs,
但现在我对它们钦佩不已
but now I respect them.
你的也不赖
Yeah, yours aren't so bad either.
下次警局野餐时
You know, for the next police picnic,
我们俩可以参加两人三足
we should do the three-legged race together.
这事定了  好了
You're on. All right.
有人吗
Hello!
你能听见我们说话吗
Can you hear us?
我猜你想第一个进去
I suppose you want to go in first.
不  你先
No. You go ahead.
那我就不谦让了
Don't mind if I do.
好
Okay.
有人在吗
Hello!
你在吗  我们是来
Are you there? We're here to--
老虎
A tiger?
是的  是只老虎
Yeah, it's a tiger.
它差点咬掉我的脸
It almost bit my face off.
等等  对了
Wait. No,
那就解释了为什么会有笼子和铁链
that explains the cage and--and the chains
还有切生肉的刀
and the butcher knives for the raw meat.
老虎  那才是他们讨价还价的东西
A tiger? That's what they were haggling over.
老虎现在频临灭绝
Yeah, well, tigers are endangered.
贩卖老虎是犯法的
Trafficking them is illegal.
我们不小心撞见了他们的非法勾当
We walked in on their operation.
此刻  撞见他们的非法勾当
Yeah, walking in on their operation
可不是我们要担心的问题
is not our problem right now.
那老虎要过来了  这才要命
That tiger walking in here is our problem.
别担心  卡塞尔  它不会走进来的
Don't worry, Castle. She's not gonna get through that wall.
回去  回去
Hey, back! Get back!
是我看错  还是它显得很饿
Is it just me, or does she look a little bit hungry?
这可糟了
Yeah, that's bad.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
我只是想让我们有多点存活的机会
I'm just gonna buy us some good will.
不不不  卡塞尔  别靠近它
No, no, no, Castle, don't go near her.
它在吃了
She's going for it.
对  当它吃完后
Yeah, and then when she's done with that,
它会索要更多
she'll want more.
天了  它要过来了
Oh, god! She's coming!
国家银行对郊外的大约一百所房子
So National Bank has close to a hundred properties
都取消了抵押回赎权
in foreclosure in the outer boroughs.
但是我们的疑犯有特殊需要
But our folks have certain needs,
因此我们排除了所有没有地下室的房子
so we filtered out all the ones without basements.
卡塞尔  我们把那洞给堵上
Come on, Castle. We gotta cover that hole.
用力推
Push.
再来
Again.
目前所知他们使用过的两处房子
The two houses we know they used
还有其他共同点  靠近高速公路出口
had other common elements-- close freeway access,
车道得足够长和宽  要容得下一辆大卡车
long, wide driveways that could fit a semi.
两处周围都是空的或无人居住的房子
And both are situated in between empty lots or unoccupied houses,
以免遇到爱管闲事的邻居
minimizing the nosy neighbor factor.
交叉对比之后
Now you cross-reference all that,
确定有11处位于郊区的房子有嫌疑
it leaves us with 11 likelies in the outer boroughs.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
把表分发下去
Divvy up the list.
让同事们去这11处房子挨个查
get unis out to all 11 properties,
要把他俩活着救出来
and let's bring them back alive.
我们躲到冰柜里吧
We get in the freezer.
门关上后  我们会窒息而死的
It'll latch, and we'll suffocate.
难道你想被吃掉吗
Would you rather be eaten?
我在想第三条出路
I was looking for option three.
到我后面躲着
Get behind me.
我想到个主意
I have a plan.
芬奇路817号
817 Fincher Drive.
八个月前被取消赎回权的工业大楼
Industrial building foreclosed on eight months ago.
看起来没人  跟刚刚找过那三个地方一样
Looks empty, just like the last three places.
我们还是溜一圈吧
Let's do a walk around.
看看后面有没有什么情况
See if there's anything in back.
好
Yeah.
这就是你的计划
This is your plan?
你知道老虎能跳多高吗
Do you know how high tigers can jump?
很高
High.
我们还活着  不是吗
Well, we're still alive, aren't we?
好吧
Okay.
埃斯波西托  来这边
Esposito, over here.
打电话叫后援
Call for backup.
记得我说过要加入马戏团吗
Remember what I said about joining the circus?
-是啊  -我改主意了
- Uh-huh. - Changed my mind.
它在玩弄我们
She's playing with us.
它会把箱子撞倒的
She's gonna knock it over.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
只能做一件事
There's only one thing to do.
像小女孩一样尖叫
Scream like little girls.
救命
Help!
-救我们出去  -等等  听
- Get us outta here! - Wait. Listen.
-来人啊  救命啊  -听到了吗
- Help! Somebody! - You hear that?
-听到了  -快来人  我们在下面
- Yeah. - Come on! We're down here!
救命  谁来救救我们
Help! Somebody, help us!
救命  救命
Help! Help!
贝克特  卡塞尔
Beckett, Castle.
埃斯波西托
Esposito.
那是只老虎吗
Is that a tiger?!
是啊  是只老虎
Yeah, yeah, that's a tiger.
把我们弄出去  好不
Hey, how about getting us out?
稍等  我们马上就来
O-okay, hang on. We'll-- we'll be right there.
放下武器  孩子们  不然我崩了你们
Drop the hardware, boys, or I'll blow you both away.
救命啊
Help! Help us!
伙计们  打开活板门
You guys, open the hatch!
-伙计们  -莱恩  埃斯波  救命
- Guys! - Ryan, Espo, help!
-把门打开  伙计们  -救命
- Open the door, boys! - Help!
放下武器
Put your weapon down.
不管你先对谁开枪
Doesn't matter which one of us you shoot first,
另外一个人都会杀了你
whoever's left standing will kill you.
那我就先把长得好看那个干掉
Maybe I'll shoot the pretty one first.
幸运的是  我不用选
Luckily, I don't gotta choose.
把枪放下
Y'all put 'em down.
你先放
You first.
杀了他们吧  老妈
Let's just kill 'em, ma.
让母老虎托尼如我们计划那样杀死其他人
Let Tony the Tiger have at the others like we planned.
把我们弄出去
Get us outta here!
开门
Open the door!
越来越危险了
The stakes are considerably raised!
救命
Help!
-救命  -救我们
- Help! - Help us!
-你的人开了枪  -救我们出去
- Your boys shoot... - Get us outta here!
我发誓  死也要
I swear, the last thing I do
射穿你的脑袋壳
is put a bullet right through your head.
-你做出选择吧  -快点啊
- Your choice. - Come on. Hurry up!
你们纽约警察一点都没有德州的吓人
You New Yorkers ain't nearly as scary as a Texas lawman.
尽管是这样
That being said,
我想你们的后援肯定马上就来了
I'm betting more of you are gonna be here soon,
我来告诉你会发生什么
so I'm gonna tell you what's gonna happen.
我和我的人会从这里离开
Me and my boys are gonna back on outta here.
你们要么选择阻止我们反被我们杀掉
You either get yourselves killed trying to stop us...
要么选择别管我们去救你们的朋友
or you can forget all about us and go save your friends.
你做出选择吧
That's your choice.
真抱歉  我没法子了
I'm so sorry. I've got nothing else.
哈维
Javi?
凯特
Kate--
不  卡塞尔  我心脏中弹可不是为了
No, Castle, I did not survive a bullet to the heart
成为老虎盘中餐
to die as tiger kibble.
放他们走
Let 'em go.
老天
Oh, god.
它把他们吃了
It ate 'em.
没把我们吃掉
It didn't eat us.
但如果你们不快点就会
But it will if you don't hurry.
地方选的不错
Nice hangout.
-不许动  -不许动
-Freeze! Freeze! - Nobody move!
举起手来
Put your hands up!
被铐到一起这么久
Handcuffed together that long?
你俩没杀掉对方真是令我惊讶
I'm surprised you two didn't kill each other.
有那么几次真是那样想的
Yeah, well, there were a couple of moments.
直到我们找到了节奏
Until we found our rhythm.
我们还是坐飞机去弗罗里达州吧
I think we'll fly to Florida.
什么
What?
我想这是你的
I believe this is yours.
-这个也是  -谢谢
- This, too. - Thank you.
你们是怎么...
How did you guys...
找到我们的
even find us?
我们跟随着你们留下的"面包屑"
Well, we followed your bread crumbs,
就找到这儿了
and it led us here.
幸运的是  我的有些警探
And lucky for all of us, some of my detectives
会告知我他们的所在地点
keep me informed as to their whereabouts.
因为你们两个
Thanks to you two,
局里要施行一个新的条例
I'm instituting a new policy in our department--
不汇报分局
No one goes anywhere...
任何人不得擅自行动
without calling it in.
谢谢你们啊  都是因为你们才这样
Thanks, you guys. Really appreciate that.
不过好在这样的话下次我们救他们的时候
Well, at least we won't have to look so hard
就不用找的这么辛苦了
next time we save your ass.
顺便说句  我想你
I missed you, by the way.
-是吗  证明给我看  -我会的
- Really? Prove it. - Oh, I'll prove it.
-那老虎咋样  -埃斯波  别提了
- How was that tiger? - Espo, stop it.
-怎么了  -虎虎生威咩
- What? - Was it gr-r-reat?
她叫露丝·斯波洛克
Her name is Ruth Spurloch.
原来她和她的儿子
And it turns out, her and her sons
是濒危老虎的大"供应商"
were major suppliers of endangered tigers
给世界各地的富人提供服务
to wealthy customers all around the world.
很难相信为了这能杀人
Hard to believe it's worth killing for.
异国动物买卖可是亿万美元的产业
The exotic animal trade's a billion-dollar industry.
而德州呢  几乎没有相关法规
And Texas, which has almost no regulations,
是世界上为数不多
is one of the few places in the world
买卖繁殖老虎合法的地方
where selling and breeding tigers is not illegal.
露丝和她的儿子靠她的繁殖场赚了几百万
Ruth and her boys were making millions off her breeding farm.
斯布纳开卡车运着它们从德里奥到纽约
Spooner would truck them from Del Rio up to New York.
富有的客户会将老虎走私过海关
And then wealthy clients would smuggle them
用自己的私人飞机将它们运走
past customs and ship 'em out on their private jets.
是的
Right.
只是  除了德州
Except outside of Texas,
买卖濒危物种是犯罪
trafficking endangered species is a criminal offense.
露丝不希望斯布纳举报她
So Ruth didn't want Spooner ratting her out.
所以当我们抵达她住所时
Which is why, when we showed up at her house,
她假扮自己是被害人  好趁机偷袭我们
she played the victim so she could get the drop on us.
是啊  用动物镇定剂把咱俩弄晕
Yeah, and knocked us out using animal tranquilizers,
肯定把我给搞出毛病了
Which can't be good for me.
嘴里还是有股味儿
I-I still have a taste in my mouth.
是啊
Yeah.
我...
Well, I...
我会把买卖动物的案子
I'm--I'm gonna turn the trafficking case
转给联调局和海关
over to the FBI and Customs.
你们可以跟他们协调一下你们的谋杀指控
You can coordinate with them on your murder charge.
谢谢  马丁内兹探员  我陪你出去
Thank you, Agent Martinez. I'll walk you out.
嘿
Hey.
如我们所料  卡车里的毛发是老虎毛
As expected, the hair from the truck is tiger,
血是生肉的血
and the blood is from raw meat.
他们用活板门给老虎丢食物
They used the hatches to throw down food to the cats
或是用麻醉镖给它们打镇定
or sedate them with darts.
那只老虎最后会怎么样
So what's gonna happen with that tiger anyway?
杀了它
Shoot him.
它会被送到保护区
She'll get transferred to a sanctuary.
或是你说那样
Or that.
最后会待在动物园吧
Probably end up in a zoo.
怎么  你想去拜访它吗
Why, you want to go and visit her?
不  谢了  饶了我吧
No. No, thanks. I'm good.
-你们去休息休息吧  -你也是
- All right, you guys get some rest. - You, too.
是啊
Yeah.
真是我最离奇的一次濒死经历
That has gotta be the strangest brush with death I've ever had.
我也是
Me, too.
不过我告诉你  这次之后
But I'll tell you, after that experience,
如果我要是再和别人铐在一起  希望那人是你
if I ever have to be hitched to someone, it would be you.
铐在一起[有结婚的意思]
Hitched?
不是那个意思
不是H开头那个铐是C开头那个铐
No, I didn't say "Hitched." I said "Cuffed."
被手铐铐在一起  不是结婚
Handcuffed, not hitched--
没有其他言外之意
The colloquial or any other connotation or meaning.
没关系  卡塞尔  我知道你的意思
It's okay, Castle. I understood what you meant.
我也表表态  如果要我跟别人铐着
And for what it's worth, if I ever have to spend
再度过一晚
another night handcuffed to someone again,
那人是你我也觉得不错
I wouldn't mind if it was you either.
真的吗
Really?
但是下次
But next time,
还是在没有老虎的情况下完成吧
let's do it without the tiger.
下次
Next time?